{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Madeleine L'Engle","incorrectAnswers":["Nathaniel Hawthorne","Robert E. Howard","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Wrinkle in Time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Casey Affleck","incorrectAnswers":["Andrew Garfield","Ryan Gosling","Viggo Mortensen"],"question":"Who won the 2016 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Lee Chandler in Manchester by the Sea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Afghanistan","Australia"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Three horizontal bands of orange, white, and green, with a blue wheel in the center.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Forbidden fruit","incorrectAnswers":["Bad apple","Posioned chalice","Sour grapes"],"question":"What is the term used to refer to the food that God instructed Adam not to eat in the bible?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Christchurch ","incorrectAnswers":["Wellington","Dunedin","Canterbury"],"question":"Which city in New Zealand is known both as 'The Garden City of the Plains'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1982","incorrectAnswers":["1977","1987","1992"],"question":"Blade Runner was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Purple","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"What Colour Are Holly Berries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The th in 'think'","incorrectAnswers":["The ch in 'cheese'","The j in 'juice'","The t in 'train'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a fricative sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","The Middle East","China"],"question":"From which part of the world do sweet potatoes originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Wind in the Willows","incorrectAnswers":["Tinker","The Sun Also Rises","The Big Sleep"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Toad'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","The Police","Led Zeppelin"],"question":"Which British rock band released the studio album 'A Night at the Opera'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Clash","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Cheap Trick"],"question":"Which British punk rock band released the song 'London Calling'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist, singer, songwriter, musician and record producer released the studio album 'The Red Shoes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Orioles","incorrectAnswers":["Ravens","Yankees","Jays"],"question":"Baseball: The Baltimore ________.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bacardi","incorrectAnswers":["Havana Club","Mount Gay","Captain Morgan's"],"question":"Which brand of rum has a bat on the label?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Murder on the Orient Express'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Don't Stop Believin'\" by Journey","incorrectAnswers":["\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"All Along the Watchtower\" by Bob Dylan","\"All I Want For Christmas Is You\" by Mariah Carey"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Just a small town girl, living in a lonely world.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is rigatoni?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["Cocteau Twins","Lostprophets","The Kinks"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Good Times Bad Times'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Jeté","incorrectAnswers":["Pirouette","Relevé","Plié"],"question":"What is the term for jumping forward from one foot to the other in ballet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sunset Boulevard","incorrectAnswers":["Broadcast News","Citizen Kane","Ghost"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Norma Desmond'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bladder","incorrectAnswers":["Stomach","Kidney","Liver"],"question":"Which organ stores urine?\n","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Alexander the Great","incorrectAnswers":["Napoleon","Julius Caesar","General Custer"],"question":"Who Had a wife named Roxana and a horse named Bacephalus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Carpenters","incorrectAnswers":["The White Stripes","Sonny & Cher","Salt-N-Pepa"],"question":"Which music had a hit with a song containing the lyrics \"Just like me, they long to be close to you\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"An American Tragedy","incorrectAnswers":["The Tin Drum","Winnie the Pooh","The Remains of the Day"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Clyde Griffiths'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'The Wall'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1971","incorrectAnswers":["1957","1964","1978"],"question":"When was the first email sent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Audrey Hepburn","incorrectAnswers":["Bette Davis","Catherine Deneuve","Selena Gomez"],"question":"Which actress starred in films including My Fair Lady and Roman Holiday?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Algeria","incorrectAnswers":["China","Mongolia","Bolivia"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"How well, not how much","incorrectAnswers":["Today it's me, tomorrow it will be you","Family over everything","I challenge you"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Quam bene non quantum'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Topiary","incorrectAnswers":["Compostation","Drapery","Pottery"],"question":"What is the art of clipping trees and hedges?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Searchers","incorrectAnswers":["Gangs of New York","Scarface","Raiders of the Lost Ark"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Ethan Edwards'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Developed the world's first vaccine (for smallpox).","incorrectAnswers":["Scientist who discovered The Theory of Relativity.","Composer and organist.","Italian explorer who landed in America."],"question":"Which of the following describes Edward Jenner?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Thomas Edison","incorrectAnswers":["Nikola Tesla","Alexander Graham Bell","Albert Einstein"],"question":"Who developed the first practical light bulb?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["The Velvet Underground","The Monkees","Fleetwood Mac"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Wouldn't It Be Nice'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gazpacho ","incorrectAnswers":["Carpaccio","Alpacho","Fropaccio"],"question":"What is the name of cold Spanish soup made from peppers and tomatoes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Diseases of the stomach and intestines","incorrectAnswers":["Drug dosage","The origin and spread of diseases","The origin of stars"],"question":"What is Gastroenterology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Smoked Haddock","incorrectAnswers":["Pickled Herring","Spiced Basa","Battered Cod"],"question":"What type of fish is in an omelette Arnold Bennett?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Austroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Koreanic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Khmer' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Buddy Holly, Big Bopper, Richie Valens","incorrectAnswers":["Bill Haley, Johnny Burnette, Chuck Berry ","Fats Domino, Jerry Lee Lewis, Willie Mae Thornton","Elvis Presley, Carl Perkins, Big Joe Turner"],"question":"Which 3 rock stars died in a plane crash on February 3rd 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Low Blood Sugar","incorrectAnswers":["High Cholesterol","High Blood Sugar","Low Cholesterol"],"question":"What Causes Hypoglycemia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["China","Southeast Asia","North America"],"question":"Where in the world are muskmelons originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Skin disease","incorrectAnswers":["Hearing","Fermentation","Games and play"],"question":"What is Dermatopathology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lungfish","incorrectAnswers":["Shark","Airfish","Bubblefish"],"question":"Which fish is able to breathe air?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Non alcoholic","incorrectAnswers":["With ice","Strong","Served with a straw"],"question":"In cocktails, what does the word 'virgin' mean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Amish","incorrectAnswers":["The Shakers","The Hutterites","The Mennonites"],"question":"Which religious sect living primarily in Ohio and southeast Pennsylvania gets its name from a 17th century Swiss Mennonite bishop?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Managua","incorrectAnswers":["Moroni","Lilongwe","Manila"],"question":"What is the capital city of Nicaragua?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Moon landing","incorrectAnswers":["Assassination of JFK","Fall of the Berlin Wall","Invention of the internet"],"question":"What historic event happened on July 20, 1969?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Amelia Earhart ","incorrectAnswers":["Beryl Markham","Mary Johnson","Elise Du Pont"],"question":"Who Was The First Woman To Fly Solo Across The Atlantic Ocean? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Art Nouveau","incorrectAnswers":["Northern Renaissance","Surrealism","High Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"The Kiss\" by Gustav Klimt is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Algae","incorrectAnswers":["Prawns","Dye","Sunlight"],"question":"Flamingos are not naturally pink. They get their color from ________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vienna","incorrectAnswers":["Baku","Ashgabat","Prague"],"question":"What is the capital city of Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Edmonton","incorrectAnswers":["Calgary","Toronto","Vancouver"],"question":"Which Canadian city is nicknamed 'Oil City'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Virginia Woolf","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","George Orwell","Joseph Conrad"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mrs Dalloway'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia ","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","India","Canada"],"question":"Lake Ladoga Is The Largest Lake In Which Country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pygmies","incorrectAnswers":["Mayans","Inuits","Bantus"],"question":"Which ethnic group of people living in Congo's Ituri Forest are the shortest in the world, with an average height of about 4'8''?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Martinique","Mali","Moldova"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ma' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Lucky Starr series'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1992","incorrectAnswers":["1987","1997","2002"],"question":"When was the first SMS message sent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Ribbon pasta","Shaped pasta","Strand pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is macaroni?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Potassium hydrogen tartrate","incorrectAnswers":["Sodium hydroxide","Trichloromethane","Methane"],"question":"What chemical compound makes cream of tartar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Horse's Mouth","incorrectAnswers":["The Member of the Wedding","Breakfast at Tiffany's","On the Road"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Gulley Jimson'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eurythmics","incorrectAnswers":["U2","Blondie","Evanescence"],"question":"Which band did Annie Lennox belong to?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Ewe","incorrectAnswers":["A Bitch","A Soar","A Cow"],"question":"What is a female sheep known as?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter and dancer released the song 'Love Never Felt So Good'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gin ","incorrectAnswers":["Rum","Vodka","Whiskey"],"question":"Which alcoholic drink would you need to make the cocktail Tom Collins?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A watch","incorrectAnswers":["A charm","A rag","An exaltation"],"question":"What is the word for a group of nightingales?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Third Reich","incorrectAnswers":["New Holland","Marburg Republic","Holy Roman Empire"],"question":"What term refers to Germany between 1933 and 1945?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hazel","incorrectAnswers":["Willow","Birch","Oak"],"question":"Which Wood Are Divining Rods Usually Made From?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Elton John","incorrectAnswers":["Mika","Madonna","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which musician released 'Your Song'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"MC Hammer","incorrectAnswers":["Vanilla Ice","Snoop Dogg","Sir Mix-a-Lot"],"question":"Stanley Burrell Is The Real Name Of Which Popular 90's Musician?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1985","incorrectAnswers":["1979","1965","1950"],"question":"In What Year Did Mikhail Gorbachev Become Leader Of The Soviet Union?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chess","incorrectAnswers":["Checkers","Backgammon","Go"],"question":"In 1988, Bobby Fischer invented a new type of clock that has since become widely used in which board game?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Liverpool","incorrectAnswers":["Manchester","Newcastle","Leeds"],"question":"Which Northern UK English city Did The Beatles Come From?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Ivory Coast","Russia"],"question":"Ropa Vieja is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dean Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Steve Martin","Tim Allen","James Wood"],"question":"Famed as a member of the Rat Pack, who died on Christmas day 1995?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ramadan","incorrectAnswers":["Passover","Yom Kippur","Lent"],"question":"What is the name for the Islamic fasting period?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","France","Chile"],"question":"In which country do they eat 12 grapes as the clock strikes midnight (one each time the clock chimes) on New Year's Eve?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1911","incorrectAnswers":["1945","1820","1515"],"question":"In What Year Was The Chinese Republic Established?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Dial Telephone","incorrectAnswers":["The Hearing Aid","The Telegram","The Microphone"],"question":"What Communication Aid Was Invented In 1905 By American Undertaker Almon Strowger","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Please Please Me'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the song 'Clocks'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Reykjavik","incorrectAnswers":["Madrid","Dublin","Lisbon"],"question":"What Is The Most Westerly European Capital City?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Islamabad","incorrectAnswers":["Zagreb","Tallinn","Tehran"],"question":"What is the capital city of Pakistan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["Saint Lucia","Malaysia","Benin"],"question":"Amsterdam is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Birdman or (The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance)","incorrectAnswers":["American Sniper","Boyhood","The Grand Budapest Hotel"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2014?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Geneva","incorrectAnswers":["Budapest","Valencia","Prague"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Switzerland?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ha*Ash","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American Latin pop duo released the album 'En vivo'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Spain ","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","England","France"],"question":"Which Country's Royalty Paid For Christopher Columbus 's First Voyage Across The Atlantic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rum","incorrectAnswers":["Brandy","Whiskey","Tequila"],"question":"What liquor made from molasses has caramel added to make the darker varieties?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cria","incorrectAnswers":["A Duckling","A Fry","A Chick"],"question":"What is a baby alpaca known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Collector","incorrectAnswers":["Alexander Pierce","Howard Stark","Groot"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Benicio Del Toro?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador ","incorrectAnswers":["Latvia","Liberia","Indonesia"],"question":"Which country has taken its name from a line of latitude?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1066","incorrectAnswers":["1000","1120","1257"],"question":"William the Conqueror was crowned on Christmas day, but in what year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"FC Dallas","incorrectAnswers":["Dallas Bills","Dallas United","Real Dallas"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Dallas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Costa Rica","France","Italy"],"question":"In which country is cachaca a popular drink?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Diapers","incorrectAnswers":["Formula Milk","Medicine","Food"],"question":"What type of baby product is Huggies?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Jenny","incorrectAnswers":["Brenda","Lisa","Julie"],"question":"Who Is Tommy Tutone Trying To Call When He Dials \"867 5309\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ten","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Three","White"],"question":"What does the word 'zehn' mean in German?","difficulty":"medium"},